<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.1">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2022-02-22T14:30:42+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Chinese Cookbook</title><subtitle>Chinese food ,China travel and everything about China</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Beijing:A historic city looking forward</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/beijing-a-historic-city-looking-forward" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Beijing:A historic city looking forward" /><published>2021-04-23T03:38:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-04-23T03:38:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/beijing-a-historic-city-looking-forward</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/beijing-a-historic-city-looking-forward"><![CDATA[<p>The rock and roll singer from Bejing, Cui Jian, once said in one of his songs: “It’s not that I don’t understand; it’s just that the world is changing too fast”. The speed with which Beijing is becoming internationalized is really startling.</p>

<p><img src="./imgs/2021042307291871.jpg" alt="" /></p>

<p>At least, in terms of the city architecture, Beijing is already an international city. One architect said that Beijing is becoming a secondhand Hong Kong. To me, Beijing seems even more like Hong Kong than Hong Kong itself. Some of the world’s foremost architects come here so they can let their imagination run wild. The National Grand Theater looks like a giant glass egg, and the national stadium looks like a big bird’s nest. You can’t say these daring designs are in keeping with the historic Beijing; they’d look just as much in place in New York City.</p>

<p>That’s not hard to understand. Many countries create new and unorthodox architectural Mega Phenomena when their economies are just starting to take off. During the 19th century, the British built the Crystal Palace and, during the 20th century, the Americans built the Empire State Building. They wanted to make it known to everybody they weren’t just economic superpowers but would also become global cultural centers.</p>

<p>Sometimes, I feel the Chinese have started copying western things too slavishly and don’t cherish their own culture enough. One newspaper commented that 70% of new buildings in Beijing were named after places in America or Europe. Many foreign tourists come to Beijing hoping to see a historic city with an Eastern flavor, but what they find is a rapidly developing modern city.</p>

<p>Maybe you don’t understand the old houses look very attractive, but they are not very suitable places to live. A photographer, who was set on living in Beijing’s siheyuan, soon found there was no running water, no decent kitchen and nowhere to park a car. In the end, he moved into a new apartment building with all the modern facilities.
The Hutong is beautiful, but they don’t provide the amenities which people of today expect. My impression is that the city is looking to the future and trying to keep up with the tides of global change, but she has no time to preserve her history.</p>

<p>It’s not as serious as you make it out to be. There are still many cultural attractions in Beijing, just as before, and a new vitality has poured into a few of the old streets. The siheyuan in the area of Shichahai, where the most beautiful old architecture is located, have been converted into European style bars and restaurants.</p>

<p>In this way, the Chinese balance yin and yang and harmonize the modern and traditional of East and West. They have made Beijing, a historic Eastern city and an international landmark as well.</p>]]></content><author><name>huujuun</name></author><category term="travel to China" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[The rock and roll singer from Bejing, Cui Jian, once said in one of his songs: “It’s not that I don’t understand; it’s just that the world is changing too fast”. The speed with which Beijing is becoming internationalized is really startling.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">136</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/136" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="136" /><published>2021-01-07T04:11:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-01-07T04:11:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/136</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/136"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name>huujuun</name></author><category term="nav" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Home</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/home" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Home" /><published>2021-01-07T04:11:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-01-07T04:11:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/home</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/home"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name>huujuun</name></author><category term="nav" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">137</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/137" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="137" /><published>2021-01-07T04:11:00+08:00</published><updated>2021-01-07T04:11:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/137</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/137"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name>huujuun</name></author><category term="nav" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Fundamental theories of Chinese Food Therapy - favors</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/fundamental-theories-of-chinese-food-therapy-favors" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Fundamental theories of Chinese Food Therapy - favors" /><published>2019-11-05T22:22:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-11-05T22:22:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/fundamental-theories-of-chinese-food-therapy-favors</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/fundamental-theories-of-chinese-food-therapy-favors"><![CDATA[<p>Four properties and five favors of Chinese herbal medicine are the essential part of the elementary therapies of TCM (traditional Chinese medicine). They are also important in the nature of food. In food therapy, foods of different properties and favors are used to balance a person’s Yin and Yang, strengthen resistance and eliminate pathogens, and help people recuperate.</p>

<p>The four natures (hot, warm, cool and cold) refer to cold and hot natures. Cool and cold are of the same kind. Cool is inferior to cold.  Warm and hot are of the same kind. Warm is inferior to hot. Cold and Cool are two of a kind, while Cool is secondary to Cold. There is another nature called neutral nature, whose medicinal preferences for cold or hot are inconspicuous. Food’s four natures (hot, warm, cool and cold) determine the effect they have on bodies. The food that can imbalance hot state, protect YIN-fuid and alleviate or eliminate heat syndromes are thus of cold or cool nature. For example, food likes watermelon or pears, which can remove heat, promote salivation and quench thirst, are cold and cool natured. Hot and warm foods can strengthen Yan Qi, imbalance cold state, relieve or eliminate cold diseases. For example, people who are afraid of cold and deficient of Yang Qi, can eat mutton, or venison, to warm the middle-energizer and withstand cold, Fresh Ginger combined with brown sugar can treat cold pain in the digestive system, by warming the middle-energizer to expel cold.</p>

<p>Five favors include Pungent, Sweet (bland), Sour (astringent), Bitter and Salty the five favors are not only the sense of taste, but also a summarization of theories. Food with different favors will demonstrate different functions.</p>

<p>The Pungent flavor has the characteristic of dispersing, moving qi and activating blood. For example, Fresh Ginger, coriander and shallot are used to treat exterior syndromes. Whereas,  Dried Tangerine Peel and Long stamen Onion Bulb are utilized in the treatment of qi-stagnation and blood stasis.</p>

<p>The Sweet flavor has the function of replenishing the deficiencies and harmonizing the middle ener gizer and relieving spasm and pain. For example, Chinese yam and Jujube are used to treat a weak body or deficiency syndrome; rhizoma dioscoreae and mel are used to treat contracture abdominalgia; Wolfberry Fruit and longan are utilized in the treatment of blood deficiency syndrome.</p>

<p>The Sour flavor has the function of stopping sweating, treating diarrhoea and preventing spermatorrhea. For instance, fructus schisandrae is utilized for the following: incessant perspiration caused by weakness, chronic diarrhea and seminal emission.</p>

<p>The Bitter favor has the function of clearing heat and purging fre, discharging stool and relieving cough and dyspnea. For example, Momordica charantia L and mustard are used to treat heat syndromes.</p>

<p>The Salty flavor has the function of softening hardness, moistening the intestines and warming the kidneys. Salty medicinal like sea-tangle and sar-gassum are often used for syndromes, such as scrofula, phlegm and abdominal mass. Jellyfish and laver are suitable for constipation due to dry feces. Mussels, prawns and holothurian can tonify kidney.</p>

<p>The Bland favor has the action of draining dampness and promoting diuresis. Bland favor medicinal, such as semen coicis, winter melon, and calabash are used to treat edema and dysuria.</p>

<p>Sweet favor and bland favor medicinal are the most frequently used in Food Therapy. Salty and sour medicinal the second, Pungent the third, and Bitter the least.</p>]]></content><author><name>huujuun</name></author><category term="Chinese food and health" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Four properties and five favors of Chinese herbal medicine are the essential part of the elementary therapies of TCM (traditional Chinese medicine). They are also important in the nature of food. In food therapy, foods of different properties and favors are used to balance a person’s Yin and Yang, strengthen resistance and eliminate pathogens, and help people recuperate.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Alcoholic Drinks and Healthcare</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/alcoholic-drinks-and-healthcare" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Alcoholic Drinks and Healthcare" /><published>2019-10-29T13:59:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-10-29T13:59:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/alcoholic-drinks-and-healthcare</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/alcoholic-drinks-and-healthcare"><![CDATA[<p>Alcoholic Drinks and Healthcare</p>

<p>Over the last decade there has been quite a shift in public opinion concerning the health effects of alcohol. Fuelled by TV programs and numerous reports in the press, most people now believe that alcohol  benefits health when drunk in moderation, which means an average of no more than one drink a day for women or two drinks a day for men.</p>

<h3>Beer and Health</h3>

<p>Studies prove that double- or triple fermentation beer is good for health, particularly given the vitamin B present in the yeast. Its beneficial effects are linked to its dietary, diuretic, and sedative properties. Though beer has the reputation of causing weight gain, its calorific value is inferior to that of apple juice or wine. Moreover, thanks to the amino acids, vitamin B, and iron it contains, beer is an energizing beverage recommended for anaemic and convalescent persons, as well as those who have lost a lot of weight. The diuretic action of beer is due to the hops resin, which stimulates the kidneys, thereby contributing to the elimination not only of excess water in the body, but also of wastes and toxins. The sedative action of the hops joined with the calorific effect of the alcohol make beer a light and pleasant sleep-inducing beverage.</p>

<h3>Health Benefits of Red Wine</h3>

<p>Experts say the health benefits of wine, especially red wine, may have gotten the most attention in recent years because of the popularity of the so-called “French Paradox’ “. The paradox refers to a study published several years ago, suggesting that the French population’s passion for wine may be responsible for keeping their heart disease rates low despite their love of rich, fatty foods. Since then, researchers have been trying to tease out what exactly in the wine seems to protect against heart disease and stroke, Studies have suggested that it may lie in the antioxidant-rich skins of the grapes used to make wine, but others have shown that antioxidants have little effect on heart health. Resveratrol might be another key ingredient in red wine that helps prevent damage to blood vessels, reduces “bad” cholesterol, and prevents blood clots. However, most research on resveratrol has been conducted on animals, not people.</p>

<h3>Chinese Medicated Liquor</h3>

<pre><code>  Since liquor itself has the effect for stimulating blood circulation and relaxing muscles and joints, it can be used to treat general asthenia, rheumatic pain, and traumatic injury. In addition, liquor is a kind of good solvent, which may extract a higher proportion of ingredients from medical material. Chinese people like to use precious medical material to make medicated liquor, which can reinforce body fluid and nourish blood. Though medicated liquor is good for human body, it cannot be drunk superfluously. A frequency of 2 or 3 times a day with each dosage measuring 10 ml to 50 ml is proper for people.
</code></pre>

<h3>Cautions</h3>

<p>Too much of a good thing is definitely a bad thing when it comes to alcohol. Alcohol abuse and alcoholism are big causes of chronic liver disease and cirrhosis. Heavy drinkers are at increased risk for certain types of cancer, and drinking is also associated with an increased risk of accidental death and mental health problems such as depression. There are certain people who should not drink- even in moderation- because they are more likely to develop alcohol-related complications. These groups include pregnant women, people who take medications that may interact with alcohol, and people who have medical conditions such as ulcers or liver conditions that might worsen with alcohol use.</p>

<h3>Chinese Food about Acohol</h3>

<p>There are a vast number of wonderful recipes which use some form of alcohol as an ingredient to achieve a desired chemical reaction in a dish. Some alcoholic beverages can help break down tough fibers via marinades. Other dishes use alcoholic content to provide entertainment, such as flambés and flaming dishes. One popular alcohol-flavored dish is Drunken Chicken. Shaoxing Drunken Chicken is cooked and marinated exclusively in historic Shaoxing Huangjiu to create a deep taste. Jiuniang is a sweet, soup-like drink made from fermented glutinous rice and yeast. Although Jiuniang is similar to unfiltered rice liquor in that it is mildly alcoholic, it contains whole rice grains and is often made with sweet Osman thus flowers. When made so, it is called Guihua Jiuniang. Jiuniang can also be served together with small unfilled tangyuan. When served in sucha manner it is called Jiuniang Tangyuan.</p>]]></content><author><name>huujuun</name></author><category term="Chinese food culture" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Alcoholic Drinks and Healthcare]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introduction to Chinese Food Therapy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/introduction-to-chinese-food-therapy" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction to Chinese Food Therapy" /><published>2019-10-29T09:13:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-10-29T09:13:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/introduction-to-chinese-food-therapy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/introduction-to-chinese-food-therapy"><![CDATA[<p>“Food Therapy”, also known as Dietary Regimen” or Diet Therapy “, has a very long history and is frequently used in China. Chinese traditional food therapy is a subject dealing with the function, compatibility, production, proper use and the relationship between food and health, under the guidance of Chinese medical theories, in addition to maintaining health and preventing diseases through food. Like pharmacotherapy, Chinese Acupuncture, Moxibustion and Chinese Tuina, food therapy is also one of the important part of Traditional Chinese Medicine (TCM).</p>

<p>Medical care, drugs and food are derived from the same roots in TCM. More than 1400 years ago, there was first “Diet Therapy” in Qianjin Yaofang (Valuable Prescriptions for Ready Reference), an ancient book written in Song Dynasty. Then, many literatures on dietetics were published one after the other. “Food Therapy” is used to preserve people’s health, while “Dietary Regimen is used to cure diseases by diet or food prohibition.</p>

<p>The function of food therapy, like the pharmacotherapy, is strengthening vital and eliminate pathogenic factor. Food therapy is a subject based on the theory of TCM, combining with Regimen Treatment and Prevention. So there are several distinguishing features below.</p>

<ol>
<li>Derivation from the Theory of TCM</li>
</ol>

<p>“Food Therapy”, one of the parts of TCM system, is absolutely based on the theory of TCM; its guiding principle is TCM, too, such as the Whole Person, the theories of therapeutic principles based on syndrome differentiation, the property and favor of food, and compatibility and incompatibility of food.</p>

<ol start="2">
<li>Unique Theory of "Dietary Regimen"</li>
</ol>

<p>In ancient China, the major theory of Dietary Regimen is feed by Measure. The option of “Based on the theory of Yin-Yang, reflected by specialized skill, and be harmonious in diet arrangement.” in Jin Dynasty is the guide line of living long, which includes two significances: controlling and adjusting. This theory has positive rules for Chinese people’s health.</p>

<ol start="3">
<li>The Emphasis on Prevention</li>
</ol>

<p>“Food Therapy” is closely connected with preventive medicine and the science of preservation. Using preventive treatment of disease”, this principle, preventing when health and avoiding affection when sick”, runs through the whole process of food therapy,</p>

<ol start="4">
<li>Determination of Treatment Based on Pathogenesis Differentiation</li>
</ol>

<p>Determination of treatment based on pathogenesis differentiation is the main feature of treating diseases in TCM, and also one of the principles of Food Therapy. The choice of food is based on pathogenesis differentiation. For example, tonics are used for deficiency syndromes; this theory can coordinate and promote the balance and stability of people’s internal environment.</p>]]></content><author><name>huujuun</name></author><category term="Chinese food and health" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[“Food Therapy”, also known as Dietary Regimen” or Diet Therapy “, has a very long history and is frequently used in China. Chinese traditional food therapy is a subject dealing with the function, compatibility, production, proper use and the relationship between food and health, under the guidance of Chinese medical theories, in addition to maintaining health and preventing diseases through food. Like pharmacotherapy, Chinese Acupuncture, Moxibustion and Chinese Tuina, food therapy is also one of the important part of Traditional Chinese Medicine (TCM).]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Liquor-Related Anecdotes about China</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/liquor-related-anecdotes-about-china" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Liquor-Related Anecdotes about China" /><published>2019-10-29T08:46:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-10-29T08:46:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/liquor-related-anecdotes-about-china</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/liquor-related-anecdotes-about-china"><![CDATA[<p>China’s history, there are a lot of anecdotes and interesting stories about liquor. Liquor, more than any other beverage, has a great impact on Chinese artists and men of letters, as it seems that many of them produce their  peak masterpieces in the state of drunkenness. In literary works, there exist a greater number of rather popular descriptions as well as stories related to alcoholic beverages.</p>

<h3>Rewarding Armies with A Single Cup of Liquor</h3>

<p>During the Spring and Autumn Period of the Eastern Zhou Dynasty，Gou Jian, King of Kingdom Yue, after being defeated by Fu Chai, King of Kingdom Wu, ordered his people to give more births so as to realize his goal of restoring a dethroned monarch. He encouraged those with more births with alcohol: the couple having one more son would be rewarded with two jars of alcohol and one dog，and the couple having one more daughter would be rewarded with two jars of alcohol and one young pig. Before King Gou Jian led his armies to suppress Kingdom Wu,his people presented mellow alcohol to him. He didn’t enjoy it by himself, but poured it into the upper part of a river and shared it with all the officers and soldiers, which highly inspired and encouraged all the armies. Nowadays, there still exists an alcoholic drink named ”Tou Lao He”，namely, Pouring Into-River Drink.</p>

<h3>Drinking Alone by Moonlight</h3>

<p>Li Bai is regarded as the greatest romantic poet of the Tang Dynasty and a representative of the high Tang culture, combination of realistic Northern culture represented by Confucian philosophy and romantic Southern culture represented by Taoist philosophy. But he could neither fulfill his Confucian ideal to serve the country nor find spiritual freedom in Taoism. So he could only chant poetry and drink liquor to drown his sorrow. Guo Moruo once compiled statistics about Li’s poems and found 17 percent of them were about drinking. Now let’s appreciate one of Li Bai’s most famous poems, Drinking Alone by Moonlight.
A cup of liquor, under the flowering trees; I drink alone, for no friend is near.
Raising my cup I beckon the bright moon;
For her, with my shadow, will make three men.
The moon, alas, is no drinker of liquor;
Listless, my shadow creeps about at my side.
Yet with the moon as friend and the shadow as slave; I must make merry before the spring is spent. To the songs I sing the moon flickers her beams; in the dance I weave my shadow tangles and breaks. While we were sober, three shared the fun; now we are drunk, each goes his way.
May we long share our odd, inanimate feast; and meet at last on the Cloudy River of the sky.</p>

<h3>Setting Fire on the First Family in the White House</h3>

<p>At the end of February 1972, Nixon returned to Washington after signing Sino-U.S. Shanghai Joint Communique with Zhou Enlai. The successful visit to China made the President feel excited. The improvised performance of Zhou Enlai in burning the liquor impressed him deeply. When he told his daughter some interesting things during his visit to China, he wanted her to sense the “interest” of Maotai. He poured a bottle of Maotai into a bowl and burned it. To his surprise, the blue flame jumped, and never died out, soon it broke the bowl. Immediately the burning Maotai flowed over the desk, and it made all members of the First Family of the U.S. feel startled. They tried all means to extinguish the fire. After that, Kissinger humorously said, “Extinguishing the fire has prevented the tragedy of a nation. Or else, Nixon government will end sooner.” In his talks with Deng Xiaoping in 1974, Kissinger also mentioned the event, and told Deng Xiaoping, insignificant way: “Do you know you almost burned the White House?” Originally, Nixon wanted to simulate the performance of Zhou Enlai, but he neglected the essential issue of quantity. What Zhou Enlai burned is a small cup, while what Nixon burned is a big bowl. It is no wonder why Maotai can make the Nixon family a group of frenzy fire fighters.</p>

<h3>Qingdao International Beer Festival</h3>

<p>Since 1991, coastal Qingdao has made a name for itself internationally with its yearly Qingdao International Beer Festival. The 2009 Qingdao International Beer Festival kicks off at Beer City, stretching for 16 full days before a closing ceremony, Every year, the Qingdao International Beer Festival provides both locals and tourists with beer drinking contests, live music, beer carnival games, and a mix of tasty food and of course, all the beer you can possibly imagine. There are over a hundred beer brands not just from China, but also from Asia, Europe, and the rest of the world. Head down to the beer halls as well and take part in the beer tasting so you can try out some of the world’s best beers. Shandong’s Tsingtao Beer Company applied for a permit to replicate Germany’s favorite beer festival in 1991, and to its surprise, the Qingdao Municipal Government wholeheartedly supported the idea.</p>]]></content><author><name>huujuun</name></author><category term="Chinese food culture" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[China’s history, there are a lot of anecdotes and interesting stories about liquor. Liquor, more than any other beverage, has a great impact on Chinese artists and men of letters, as it seems that many of them produce their peak masterpieces in the state of drunkenness. In literary works, there exist a greater number of rather popular descriptions as well as stories related to alcoholic beverages.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Ganbei(Cheers) Through Ages</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/ganbeicheers-through-ages" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Ganbei(Cheers) Through Ages" /><published>2019-10-28T12:06:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-10-28T12:06:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/ganbeicheers-through-ages</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/ganbeicheers-through-ages"><![CDATA[<p>In China, the life of every person should have pauses for JiuXi (literally liquor drinking banquets). When someone builds a new house, marries, starts a business, makes a fortune, or celebrates birthday, he should invite people in for a drink. “If we are good friends, then drink up; if not, then just take a sip” is a common phrase exchanged during gatherings.</p>

<h3>Versatile Traditional Ganbei Culture</h3>

<p>The symbolic serving and drinking of liquor on various ccasions and in different places can convey many meanings. It can express either joy or sorrow. In China, there is a saying that a thousand cups of liquor is not too much when bosom friends meet together”, which indicates the happiness between two confidants; whereas a verse by Li Bai, a noted poet in the Tang Dynasty says,  “releasing melancholy with liquor, but adding more” , suggests a touch of sadness.</p>

<p>In ancient times, before a battle, a general would feast his soldiers with liquor and meat. If they won the battle, they would be rewarded with good liquor. If a warrior fell in the battle, his fellows would scatter liquor on the ground as part of a memorial ceremony. Liquor is intimately connected with most Chinese men of letters. There are many famous Chinese poets and artists who craft their masterpieces after getting “drunk” .</p>

<p>Under the marriage tradition of Daur nationality in China, after the bride’s relatives accompany the bride to the bridegroom’s home, the bridegroom’s parents should entertain the bride’s relatives with two cups of liquor, which is named Welcome Drink”. The relatives should drink it up in order to show they have been united as one family. In the Nu nationality area in Yunnan Province, all the families of the village should come to condole with liquor when someone is dead. The wizard pours some liquor into the dead person’s mouth, while all the people on the spot have a cup of liquor, which is named “Farewell Drink”.</p>

<h3>Protocol of Ganbei at Dinner Table</h3>

<p>When drinking liquor at table, both the host and the guests are expected to observe certain rules of etiquette and behavior. Atypical Jiu Xi will involve 8 12 people seated around a large roundtable, in a private room with numerous dishes. At least two glasses are placed in front of each person: a large one for beer and a shot glass for baijiu. There is a whole protocol in Ganbei. The glass should be full of liquor, else it is thought that due respect is lacking. When making a Ganbei, everyone is required to stand and lightly touch each other’ s cup, ensuring that the junior ‘s cup is held lower than that of his superior. The cup should be emptied and inverted to show that no liquor remains.</p>

<p>The host will start and propose a Ganbei with baijiu, then the guest; after that the second host would make a Ganbei, and so on. Protocol will then allow a free-for -all, where everyone makes Ganbei in no specific order. In addition, there are fines (i.e. one has to drink one shot for being late) and many unwritten rules. If someone tries not to drink, he will have to drink double. If one volunteers to drink for a helpless associate, he will have to drink his friend’s shot and then his own. It is customary to be under attack from the whole table; especially if one is the highest-ranking of the group. The usual procedure is that each person at, say, a table of ten, rises to drink with him, each in turn. Do the math: after ten rounds they each have one shot, he will have ten.</p>]]></content><author><name>huujuun</name></author><category term="Chinese food culture" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In China, the life of every person should have pauses for JiuXi (literally liquor drinking banquets). When someone builds a new house, marries, starts a business, makes a fortune, or celebrates birthday, he should invite people in for a drink. “If we are good friends, then drink up; if not, then just take a sip” is a common phrase exchanged during gatherings.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">100-odd Years History of Changyu(Zhangyu)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/100-odd-years-history-of-changyuzhangyu" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="100-odd Years History of Changyu(Zhangyu)" /><published>2019-10-27T12:49:00+08:00</published><updated>2019-10-27T12:49:00+08:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/100-odd-years-history-of-changyuzhangyu</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/100-odd-years-history-of-changyuzhangyu"><![CDATA[<p>In recent years, wine has gained popularity as more people begin to value health when choosing liquor products. Wine provides the body with energy, with substances that aid digestion and with small amounts of minerals and vitamins. Moderate consumption of red wine on a regular basis can also stimulate the appetite，boost the immune system， protect against heart disease，and block cancer formation.</p>

<h3>Founder of Changyu - Zhang Bishi</h3>

<p>In 1871, Mr. Zhang Bishi was invited by a Dutch friend to the French embassy in Jakarta for a party. The French consulate hosted a very formal high-class event where premium French wines were served. The bouquet and taste of these French wines impressed Mr. Bishi immensely.</p>

<p>Li Hongzhang assisted Mr. Zhang Bishi in gaining the Chinese business license and in fact it was Mr. Li’s personal sealon the original business license of Changyu Winery. Li Hongzhang took Changyu Winery as a symbol of his initiative known a Westernization Movement”, established to encourage Chinese businessmen to begin new industry and to compete internationally. The benefits afforded Changyu Winery in their business license stated Changyu enjoyed 3 years of free tax, and Chinese o1foreign companies in Liaoning, Hebei and Shandong provinces could not be involved in the wine industry for the first 15 years of Changyu’s license.  Changyu Winery did not disappoint LHongzhang, The wine it produced was not only of high quality wine, but quickly became popular and was under quite high demand. “Why don’t I set up a winery?” This idea grew in his mind until he formed a plan, and finally he established Changyu Winery in 1892.</p>

<p>Mr. Zhang Bishi was active in donating money to the national revolution led by Sun Yet-sun. In 1912 when Mr. Sun Yet sun visited Changyu Winery and tasted Changyu wine, he inscribed the characters Pin Zhong Li Quan. Mr. Zhang Xueliang gave Changyu Winery the inscription of Gui Dun Yi Mou. Gui Dun means Bai Gui and Yi Dun who were two famous businessmen in the Spring-Autumn Period of Chinese history. Zhang Xueliang took this to mean that Changyu Winery had special company management and experience.</p>

<h3>Establishment of the Brand</h3>

<p>The first batch of wine was made in 1896， but Changyu Winery did not launch it at once. Instead, they put the wines in the cellar for 18 years. In 1914， these wines were tested and declared excellent with the right maturation and color. After this, Changyu Winery applied for trademark and released the wines tothe market. Changyu Winery knew the importance of establishing its own brand and did a lot of advertisement for Changyu wine. Billboards were put up at ports, bus and train stations. Dishware with the name of the winery was served to hotels and restaurants. At festivals, big trucks would carry big barrels to parade and give small bottles of wine to the audience as gift. Premier Zhou Enlai used to pay a lot of attention to Changyu wine. In 1954, Premier Zhou chose Maotai and Changyu wine to be sent to Geneva.</p>

<p>ln 2001, Changyu entered into a joint venture with the Castel Group, the largest grower and distributor of wine in France and the second largest beverage distributor in the world. Wine chateaus are traditional tourist resorts in European and North and South American countries. With 100-odd years’ history of winemaking, Changyu launched China’s first tourist route with a wine culture theme, the Chateau Changyu-Castel. Changyu Group has been ranked as the 10th largest winery in the world in2008. This is the first time that an Asian winery has entered the top 10 global wineries.</p>

<h3>the trademark of Jiebaina and Changyu</h3>

<p>In 2008, the Trademark Review and Adjudication Board of the State Administration for Industry and Commerce announced that Changyu Wine Company is the owner of the trademark Jiebaina. This brought an end to the six-year dispute about the intellectual property rights of Jiebaina. However, other wine companies, including Great Wall, Weilong Grape Wine, and Dynasty Winery, handed in a joint application, asking the administration to withdraw the trademark license. Their reason was that Jiebaina was a variety of grape and a common name for grape products. Therefore, Changyu should not have the exclusive right for it. Changyu retorted that Jiebaina was an original brand of the company and its statement was supported by departments such as the Sub-council of Grape and Wine of the Chinese Society for Horticultural Science, and the Chinese Society for Viticulture. According to these departments, Jiebaina was not included in the formal names of existing varieties of grapes.</p>]]></content><author><name>huujuun</name></author><category term="Chinese food culture" /><summary type="html"><![CDATA[In recent years, wine has gained popularity as more people begin to value health when choosing liquor products. Wine provides the body with energy, with substances that aid digestion and with small amounts of minerals and vitamins. Moderate consumption of red wine on a regular basis can also stimulate the appetite，boost the immune system， protect against heart disease，and block cancer formation.]]></summary></entry></feed>